export const quizQuestions_8 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the "useRef" hook in React?',
      choices: ['To interact directly with the DOM', 'To store the previous state', 'To create a ref to a function', 'To manage state in a component'],
      correctAnswer: 'To interact directly with the DOM',
    },
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is NOT a feature of React?',
      choices: ['Virtual DOM', 'Two-way data binding', 'JSX', 'Component-based architecture'],
      correctAnswer: 'Two-way data binding',
    },
    {
      question: 'How does React handle user inputs in forms?',
      choices: ['Using controlled components', 'With uncontrolled components', 'Through external libraries', 'By direct DOM manipulation'],
      correctAnswer: 'Using controlled components',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the primary role of the "key" prop when rendering lists of elements in React?',
      choices: ['To enable global access to elements', 'To ensure each element has a unique identifier', 'For optimization during re-rendering processes', 'To create a link between different list items'],
      correctAnswer: 'For optimization during re-rendering processes',
    },
    {
      question: 'In React, what is the common use case for the "useContext" hook?',
      choices: ['To access the current context value', 'To create a new context', 'To manage state globally', 'To replace Redux'],
      correctAnswer: 'To access the current context value',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is a typical use case for the "useReducer" hook in React?',
      choices: ['For managing simple state transitions', 'For handling local component state', 'For state management in complex components with multiple sub-values', 'For replacing the useState hook in all scenarios'],
      correctAnswer: 'For state management in complex components with multiple sub-values',
    },
    {
      question: 'How do you conditionally render components in React?',
      choices: ['Using the "if" statement inside JSX', 'With the ternary operator or logical && operator inside JSX', 'By using a switch statement', 'React does not support conditional rendering'],
      correctAnswer: 'With the ternary operator or logical && operator inside JSX',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the primary function of the "useEffect" hook in React?',
      choices: ['To handle component lifecycle events', 'To fetch data', 'To perform side effects in functional components', 'All of the above'],
      correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
    },
    {
      question: 'In React, what is a "pure component"?',
      choices: ['A component that renders UI without any state or props', 'A component that doesn’t re-render if its state or props haven’t changed', 'A component without any lifecycle methods', 'A function component using only React hooks'],
      correctAnswer: 'A component that doesn’t re-render if its state or props haven’t changed',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the recommended way to pass information deep down the component tree in React without using props?',
      choices: ['State lifting', 'Context API', 'Higher-Order Components', 'Prop drilling'],
      correctAnswer: 'Context API',
    }
  ]
};
